<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dicamba | Lucas K. Bobadilla</title>
    <link>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/tag/dicamba/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/tag/dicamba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>dicamba</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 17:32:05 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/media/icon_hu0122ad418663dde9f9bf0938116b612a_41144_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>dicamba</title>
      <link>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/tag/dicamba/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dicamba resistance evolution in Amaranthus tuberculatus</title>
      <link>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/project/dicamba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 17:32:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/project/dicamba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waterhemp [&lt;em&gt;Amaranthus tuberculatus&lt;/em&gt; (Moq.) Sauer] is one of the most troublesome weed species in the midwestern United States. &lt;em&gt;Amaranthus tuberculatus&lt;/em&gt; has prolific seed production and can drastically reduce soybean and corn yields by 40% to 70%, respectively. The rapid evolution and selection of herbicide-resistance traits in A. tuberculatus represent a major challenge in managing this species. Amaranthus tuberculatus resistant to acetolactate synthase (ALS) and photosystem II (PSII) inhibitors was first identified in the 1990s; currently, resistance to herbicides from seven SOA groups (Groups 2, 4, 5, 9, 14, 15, 27) has been documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dicamba is a synthetic auxin herbicide that has been commercially available since the late 1960s to control a wide range of broadleaf weeds. Dicamba is an important herbicide in corn production and also in soybean following the release of dicamba-resistant soybean cultivars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has the focus the characterization of first documented dicamba resistance case in &lt;em&gt;Amaranthus tuberculatus&lt;/em&gt;. The project was divided into two steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 1: &lt;strong&gt;Quantification of the resistance level and understanding of the inheritance patterns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step was recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/publication/bobadilla-characterization-inheritance-dicamba-2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; on Weed Science and details can be found in the peer reviewed manuscript. In fact, the paper was featured in the cover of the journal edition and was &lt;a href=&#34;https://aces.illinois.edu/news/first-dicamba-resistant-waterhemp-reported-illinois&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;featured in multiple News outlet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step 2: &lt;strong&gt;Transcriptome and expression variation in Dicamba resistance waterhemp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This second step consists of an RNA-seq study to identify the putative candidate genes involved with dicamba resistance. Currently, I already identified key genes that could play a role in dicamba resistance and a manuscript is on the writing process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization and Inheritance of Dicamba Resistance in a Multiple-Resistant Waterhemp (emphAmaranthusemph Tuberculatus) Population from Illinois</title>
      <link>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/publication/bobadilla-characterization-inheritance-dicamba-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/publication/bobadilla-characterization-inheritance-dicamba-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Resistance to Diquat in Glyphosate/Paraquat-Resistant Hairy Fleabane (Conyza Bonariensis) and Horseweed (Conyza Canadensis) and Confirmation of 2,4-D Resistance in Conyza Bonariensis</title>
      <link>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/publication/moretti-crossresistance-diquat-glyphosate-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lucaskbobadilla.github.io/publication/moretti-crossresistance-diquat-glyphosate-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
